Guide to the Nichols Family Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1769-1873; Series I; 6.67; (19 boxes)
  - Hardy, Sir Thomas Duffus, 1804-1878. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Record Office Tower, 1854 Feb 24 (Box 8)
    About an annotation in a book belonging to the library of John Nichols, John Gough Nichols's grandfather.
  - Harford, John Scandrett, 1787-1866. AL (3d person) to John Gough Nichols, Athenaeum, 1840 Jul 16 (Box 8)
    Forwards friend's reply to a letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Harral, Thomas, d. 1853. ALS to Nichols & Co., Bedford Tow, 1832 Aug 27 (Box 8)
    Writes of his intention to let the Gentleman's Magazine publish his memoirs. The letter is written on a 2-page advertisment for La Cour des Dames, a new publication edited by Harral.
  - Harris, John, 1756-1846. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], [n.p.], 1826 Apr 10 (Box 8)
    On expenses of publishing a book.
  - Hawes, Herbert. 3 ALS to Anne Nichols, [v.p.], 1831 Mar 12-1859 Feb 12 (Box 8)
    Declines her assistance in an election at the London Orphan House and asks to copy an engraving of hers.
  - Heberden, William, 1710-1801. AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Pall Mall, 1780 Jan 27 (Box 8)
    Informs Nichols that William Bowyer was never a candidate for a degree at the university.
  - Hedgeland, J. P. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Grove Place, 1831 Mar 15 (Box 8)
    Thanks Nichols for the Gentleman's Magazine 's favorable review of his book about St. Neots Windows and offers to permit him to sell the remaining copies.
  - Helsby, J. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Manchester, 1871 May 20 (Box 8)
    Arranges for a meeting.
  - Helsby, Thomas. 2 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Manchester, 1871 Mar 22-May 20 (Box 8)
    Concerns corrections of proofs for his book.
  - Henslowe, Cecilia Maria. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Portman Square, 1841 Jun 4 (Box 8)
  - Henslowe, Edward. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Gravesend, Kent, 1852 Dec 1 (Box 8)
    Excuses Mrs. Henslowe (his mother?) for her advanced age of 84 years.
  - Herrich, William. 10 ALS and 1 AL to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1826-48 Jul 9 (Box 8)
    Personal correspondence concerning friends, food, health, books, prints and grandchildren.
  - Hersee, W. "A tribute to the memory of the late J. Nichols Esq.," [n.p.], 1826 Dec (Box 8)
    Holograph poem, signed.
  - Heytesbury, William A'Court, 1st baron, 1779-1860. LS to [Nichols & Co.], Heytesbury, 1843 Sep 12 (Box 8)
    Wants to know if the two recently received volumes of the History of Salisbury terminate Sir Richard Hoare's History of South Wales.
  - Hiffe, Thomas, b. 1782. 3 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Hinckley, 1847 Dec-1863 Jan (Box 8)
    Asks for "assistance that would relieve my necessities with a small pecuniary aid or a few articles of clothing."
  - Hills, Philip. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Colne Park, 1818 Aug 17 (Box 8)
    Orders books.
  - Hoare, Sir Richard Colt, 2d Bart., 1758-1838. 42 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1801 Mar 3-1821 Jun 6 (Box 8)
    Long correspondence between printer and historian about business, research and personal matters.
  - Hobhouse, Sir Benjamin, 1st Bart., 1757-1831. Letter (copy) to Daniel Moore, Manchester buildings, 1820 Dec 9 (Box 8)
  - Hodgkin, J. ALS to John Nichols, Elmswell, 1787 Aug 18 (Box 8)
  - Hodgkinson, J. ALS to John Nichols, Snow Hill, 1803 Jul 18 (Box 8)
    Sent material to be printed.
  - Hodgson, James. ALS to Nichols & Co., [n.p.], [n.y.] Jul 16 (Box 8)
  - Hodgson, W. ALS to Nichols & Co., Hodsden, 1816 Feb 23 (Box 8)
  - Hodson, Margaret (Holford), 1778-1852. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Chester, 1815 Oct 31 (Box 8)
    Asks why the Gentleman's Magazine did not run a larger obituary about the death of Joseph Palmer. Includes draft of Nichols's response.
  - Holbrooke, Frederick. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Bedford Square, 1811 Jan 26 (Box 8)
    Asks whether some of his sketches may be printed in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Hole, Richard, 1746-1803. 3 ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 8)
  - Hole, Robert, 1767-1826. 3 ALS to Nichols & Co., [v.p.], 1815 Sep 3-1816 Mar 14 (Box 8)
    Orders and payments for books.
  - Holliday, John, 1730?-1801. ALS to John Nichols, Lincoln's Inn, [n.y.] Feb 3 (Box 8)
    Mr. Holliday "took fair occasion to impress on Young Mr. Nichols's Mind how excellent a Father he had, who had declined the high honor of being elected an alderman of London, for the Benefit of his Family & Improvement of his Fortune in Business."
  - Hollis, Caroline. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Apollo Buildings, 1843 Dec 26 (Box 8)
    About her late brother's engravings.
  - Hollis, George, 1793-1842
    - 49 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Oxford, 1816 Sep-1840 Sep 14 (Box 8)
      Letters from an engraver to his publisher. Most relate to plates engraved by Hollis for Nichols.
    - 13 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Walworth, 1835 Jan 2-1839 Jan 26 (Box 8)
      About engravings done for Nichols.
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., [n.p.], 1840 Apr 22 (Box 8)
      Asks for more time to complete engraving.
  - Hollis, John. 2 ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1846 Oct 8 (Box 8)
    Sends article he wants printed in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Hollis, Mary Ann. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1843 Oct 18 (Box 8)
    Advises Nichols of the death of her son Thomas and asks for settlement in respect to work done by him.
  - Hollis, Thomas, 1818-1843
    - 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Gloucester Buildings, Walworth, 1842 Mar 2 (Box 8)
      About his father's death. Thanks Nichols for the obituary which appeared in the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - 5 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Walworth, 1840 Jun 21-1842 Jun 13 (Box 8)
      In one letter Hollis says that he loves one of Nichols's sisters and asks, should she consent to marry him, would Mr. and Mrs. John B. Nichols approve. Endorsed on the letter is J. B. Nichols's reply that Hollis is too young and there will be no marriage. The other letters concern engravings and illustrations.
  - Holmes, John, 1800-1854. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Retford, 1820 Aug 1, 1840 Dec 2 (Box 9)
  - Hommey, M. F. 8 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Charlton, 1818 Aug 23-1821 Aug 14 (Box 9)
    About articles for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Hood, Edward. ALS to John Nichols, Temple, 1815 Jul 13 (Box 9)
  - Hood, William. 3 ALS and 4 AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Temple, 1810 Oct 24-1826 Sep 26 (Box 9)
    On antiquarian and personal matters.
  - Hooker, T. R. ALS to John Bridges, Brighton, 1824 (Box 9)
    That Mr. Nichols's manuscript will be picked up on Monday.
  - Hooper, Stephen. ALS to John Nichols, Boston, 1819 May 30 (Box 9)
    Lauds Nichols's Literary Anecdotes of the 18th Century as a "more valuable treasury of information, & copious collection of materials for future history, than is elsewhere to be found."
  - Hopkinson, A. ALS to John Nichols, Morton, 1815 Apr 19 (Box 9)
    Asks for issue of Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Hopkinson, Samuel. 3 ALS to John Nichols, Morton, 1809 Jan 16-1814 Jan 20 (Box 9)
    Book orders and personal matters.
  - Hopkinson, William. 2 ALS to Nichols & Co., Bourn, 1812 Jun 27 (Box 9)
  - Horne, Felicia Elizabeth. ALS and AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Uxbridge Common, 1808 Jan 6, 1811 Nov 11 (Box 9)
  - Horsley, Samuel, Bp. of St. Asaph, 1733-1806. 4 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1776 Jul 6-1792 Oct 3 (Box 9)
    About printing and religious controversies.
  - Hoskins, George. ALS to Nichols & Co., Jermyn St., [1835 or later] (Box 9)
    Offers to pay part of the printing costs for his articles about Ethiopia if Nichols agrees not to edit it.
  - Howard, Edward John, d. 1868. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Wolverhampton, 1844 Aug 5 (Box 9)
    Asks that a book be forwarded to his new address.
  - Howard, Henry. ALS to Nichols & Co., Lower Brook St., 1826 Jun 15 (Box 9)
    Sends an order from Sir Richard Hoare.
  - Howe, Sarah Charlotte (Howe) Waller, Baroness, 1762-1835. AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Arlington Street, 1810 Jul 2 (Box 9)
    Provides new mailing address.
  - Howe of Langar, Sophia Charlotte (Howe) Curzon Waller, Baroness, 1762-1835. AL to Mr. Nichols, 1812 Feb 13 (Box 9)
  - Howlett, Bartholomew, 1767-1827. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Clapham, 1814 Sep 25 (Box 9)
    On engravings done for Nichols.
  - Hunter, Joseph, 1783-1861
    - ALS to John Nichols, Bath, 1814 May 6 (Box 9)
      Information for Nichols's Literary Anecdotes of the 18th Century.
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Torrington Square, 1845 Jan 23 (Box 9)
      About antiquarian matters for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Huntingford, George Isaac, Bp. of Hereford, 1748-1832. 6 ALS to John Nichols, Winchester College, 1781 Jan 13-1788 Jan 17 (Box 9)
    About his poetry published by Nichols and refutation of criticism of his work.
  - Hurd, R. 5 ALS to John Nichols, Worcester, 1808 Nov 7-1816 Feb 26 (Box 9)
    About the work of his uncle, Bishop Hurd. Also orders books.
  - Hurd, Richard, Bp. of Worcester, 1720-1808. 6 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1778 Jul 29-1800 Aug 12 (Box 9)
    About corrections and criticisms of proofs.
  - Hurst, Nicholas. ALS to John Nichols, Clifton, 1817 Sep 20 (Box 9)
    Correction of a ballad which appeared in the History of Hinckley.
  - Hurst, William. 2 ALS to John Nichols, Hinckley, 1781 Nov 1, Nov 24 (Box 9)
    On financial matters.
  - Hutchinson, B. ALS to John Nichols, Rimbolton, 1787 Feb 4 (Box 9)
    Engages Nichols to publish his Natural History and Antiquities of Huntingdon.
  - Hutchinson, Benjamin. ALS to John Nichols, Southwall, 1800 Feb 22 (Box 9)
    About the Gentleman's Magazine and mutual friends.
  - Hutchinson, William, 1732-1814. 34 ALS to John Nichols, Barnard Castle, 1774 Dec 13-1806 Jun 30 (Box 9)
    Long correspondence between historian and his publisher concerning publication problems, proofs, personal communications and literary gossip. Accompanied by printed prospectuses of Hutchinson's works and receipts.
  - Hutton, Catherine, 1756-1846. 15 ALS to John Nichols and John Bowyer Nichols, Bennett's Hill, 1813 Nov 22-1841 Mar 22 (Box 9)
    About the posthumous publication of some of her father's works and her autograph collection.
  - Hutton, George Henry, d. 1827. ALS, 3 AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Southampton Row, [1823] Mar 11-Jun 16 (Box 9)
    About the publication of his father's obituary and memoirs in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Hutton, William, 1723-1815. 11 ALS to John Nichols, Birmingham, 1792 May 5-1810 May 11 (Box 9)
    Instructions for printing and corrections of proofs.
  - Hyatt, M. H. 7 ALS to Nichols & Co., [v.p.], 1810 Nov 21-1820 Jul 19 (Box 9)
    On publication instructions and book orders.
  - Inglis, Sir Hugh, Bart. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Soho Square, 1810 Jan 18 (Box 10)
    Asks Nichols to insert obituary in next Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Ingram, James, 1774-1850. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Oxford, [1824 or later] Apr 24 (Box 10)
    Asks about the disposal of 200 copies of Nichols's inaugural address recently discovered.
  - Irby, W. 3 AL (3d person) to John Nichols, 1804 Aug 15-1807 Dec 10 (Box 10)
  - Isted, Mrs. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., St. James's Hotel, [n.y.] Jul9 (Box 10)
    Arranges meeting with John and John Bowyer Nichols.
  - Irving, Henry. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Parliament St., 1847 May 20 (Box 10)
    Employee reporting on his activities.
  - Jackson, John. ALS to John Nichols, Sea Policy Stamp Office, n.d. (Box 10)
    Arranges meeting to discuss a "Book I am desirous you should Print for me."
  - Jackson, William. ALS to John Nichols, Canterbury, 1783 Feb 22 (Box 10)
  - Jacob, William, 1762?-1851. ALS to Nichols & Co., Chelsham Lodge, 1818 Oct 31 (Box 10)
  - Jago, John. ALS to [John Nichols?], Tavistock, Devon, n.d. (Box 10)
    Payment for publications.
  - Jarvis, Richard. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Cambridge Terrace, 1848 Jan 11 (Box 10)
  - Jarvis, William John. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Hurley, 1848 Oct 7 (Box 10)
    About a real estate transaction.
  - Jasper, Mr. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1821 Nov 15 (Box 10)
    Letter to the Gentleman's Magazine about the Magna Charta.
  - Jenkins, Rufus. ALS to John Nichols, Somerset, 1805 Feb 3 (Box 10)
    On "historical Remains" in the County of Dorset. Mentions Richard Gough.
  - Jennings, John. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Westminster, 1862 Mar 17 (Box 10)
    About baptism for children.
  - Jermyn, Latitia. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Ipswich, 1819 May 8, Sep 20 (Box 10)
    About obituary articles for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Jerningham, Edward, 1727-1812. Letter (copy) to John Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 10)
  - Jesse, Edward, 1780-1868. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Hampton Court, 1835 Apr 18 (Box 10)
    Asks that a review of his be published in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Jodrell, Richard Paul, 1745-1831. ALS and letter (copy) to John Nichols, Oxfordshire, 1784 Jul 30, Sep 19 (Box 10)
    About the printing of Mr. Jodrell's tragedy, The Persian Heroine.
  - Johnes, Thomas, 1748-1816. 10 ALS to John Nichols, Hafod, 1801 May 15-1816 Feb 5 (Box 10)
    About his translations and antiquarian works printed by Nichols.
  - Johns, Henry W. ALS to John Nichols, Blandford, 1817 Sep 27 (Box 10)
    Offers to send Nichols some letters to George Hardinge for his proposed biography.
  - Johnson, Francis. 4 ALS to [John Nichols], Spalding, 1781 Sep 10-1794 Feb 14 (Box 11)
    Friendly letters.
  - Johnson, Goddard. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Ely Place, 1846 Sep 10 (Box 11)
    Declines invitation.
  - Johnson, Isaac. 6 ALS to John Nichols, Woodbridge, 1788 Apr 21-1819 Dec 23 (Box 11)
    About drawings done for Nichols. Accompanied by 5 receipts to Johnson for services rendered.
  - Johnson, J. ALS to [John Nichols], Shrewsbury, 1813 May 4 (Box 11)
    Asks Nichols for any information he might have about his family Johnson in Leicestershire.
  - Johnson, John, 1754-1814. 4 ALS and 1 AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Camden Town, 1807 Jul 8-1808 Oct 12 (Box 11)
    Concerns the buildings he designed in Leicestershire.
  - Jolliffe, Hylton, d. 1854. ALS to [John Nichols?], Jermyn St. (Box 11)
  - Jones, Edward, 1777-1837. 12 ALS to Nichols & Co., Loddington, 1801 Jan 29-1814 Nov 7 (Box 11)
    About the Gentleman's Magazine and literary subjects.
  - Jones, Henry. ALS to [John Nichols], Chatham, 1769 Feb 16 (Box 11)
    Sends list of monumental inscriptions in a Chatham churchyard.
  - Jones, J. ALS to Nichols & Co., Ave Maria Lane, 1820 Dec 20 (Box 11)
    Sends publishing advice.
  - Jones, John. ALS to John Nichols, Brown Lane, Spital Fields, 1803 Jun 20 (Box 11)
    Asks business favor.
  - Jones, Stephen, 1763-1827
    - 5 ALS to John Nichols, Red Lion Passage, 1812 Aug 4-1816 Mar 7 (Box 11)
      Thanks Nichols for the gift of his Literary Anecdotes of the Eighteenth Century.
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Red Lion Passage, Fleet Street, 1817 Mar 12 (Box 11)
  - Jones, W. L. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Beaumaris, 1848 Oct 13 (Box 11)
    Thanks Nichols for correcting proofs.
  - Justamond, A. 2 ALS and 1 AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., [n.p.] (Box 11)
    About research done for prospective articles.
  - Kempe, Alfred. Fragment, signed, to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1829 Nov 20 (Box 11)
    About research done for Nichols.
  - Kerrison, Robert Masters. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Upper Brook St., 1847 Jan 12-14 (Box 11)
    Thanks Nichols for the present of a book and sends one to be inspected.
  - Knight, Frederick. ALS to John Gough Nichols, London Bridge, 1864 Oct 29 (Box 11)
    Asks him to return his season ticket for the railroad. On the verso are genealogical notes in Nichols's hand.
  - Knight, J. F. ALS to [John Nichols], Andorston, 1803 Oct 18 (Box 11)
    Addition to Nichols's History of Dorset.
  - Layton, William, 1750-1831. ALS to John Nichols, Ipswich, 1826 Mar 4 (Box 11)
    Thanks Nichols for a recently received book and sends him a letter of antiquarian interest.
  - Le Breton, A. H. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Portman Square, 1866 Apr 2 (Box 11)
  - Leman, Thomas, 1751-1826. ALS (fragment) to John Nichols, Rivers St., 1793 Nov 24 (Box 11)
  - Lindsay, John. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Cork, 1832 Mar 31 (Box 11)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine concerning Roman coins.
  - Lipscomb, George, 1773-1846. "Obituary of the Reverend David Roderick," [n.p.], 1830 (Box 11)
    Holograph, signed. Obituary for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Lismore, Frances (Ponsonby) O'Callagan, baroness, 1757-1827. ALS (3d person) to Mr. Edwards, Turnbridge Wells, [n.y.] Jun 19 (Box 12)
    Business instructions.
  - Lloyd, Charles, 1748-1828. ALS to John Nichols, Bath, 1822 Mar 6 (Box 12)
    Asks Nichols to insert in the Gentleman's Magazine a memorial written by his son about his recently deceased mother.
  - Lorrouche, C. W. ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1838 (Box 12)
    Sends copy of letter written by Sir John Vanbrugh in 1713.
  - Lower, Mark Anthony, 1813-1876. ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1866 Aug 3 (Box 12)
    On antiquarian subjects such as genealogies and family arms.
  - Lunn, Charles. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Hampshire, 1866 Oct 18 (Box 12)
  - M. ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1831 May 9 (Box 12)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine accompanied by a copy of a letter from George Vertue to Charles Christian about the portraits of Milton.
  - Mackinnon, William Alexander, 1784-1870. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Upper Seymour Street West, 1815 Nov 16, 25 (Box 12)
    Concerns memoirs of Mackinnon's father-in-law Joseph Palmer, which Mackinnon wrote and Nichols published.
  - Manchester, George Montague, 6th Duke of, 1799-1855. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Kimbolton, 1851 Feb 10 (Box 12)
    Correction of article in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Mansel, J. T. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Dunkeswell, Hariton, 1842 Jun 15 (Box 12)
  - Mansell, E. J. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Cheadle, 1832 Jan 4 (Box 12)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine about Cheadle and her ancient remains.
  - Markland, Jeremiah, 1693-1776. ALS to William Bowyer, Uckfield, 1746 Sep 29 (Box 12)
    Orders the destruction of the remaining copies of Markland's edition of the Sylvae of Statius which Bowyer had printed in 1728.
  - Martin, Charles Wykham. 5 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Leeds, 1867 Mar 26-1868 Mar 5 (Box 12)
    On the genuineness of Franklin seals and other antiquarian objects.
  - Martin, John. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1836 Oct (Box 12)
  - Martin, John, 1791-1855. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Woburn Abbey, 1837 Jan 19 (Box 12)
    Wants to know if his copy of a book is complete.
  - Martyn, Thomas, 1735-1825. ALS to [John Nichols?], Pertenhall, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Michael, J. G. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 12)
    About plants, friends and family.
  - Millhouse, Robert, 1788-1839. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Nottingham, 1823 Jan 10, 1827 Feb 3 (Box 12)
    Please for an advance of £4 "on the merits of my present publication." Thanks Nichols "for your very liberal and friendly notice of my Song of the Patriot
  - Monk, James Henry, Bp. of Gloucester and Bristol, 1784-1856. AL (3d person) to John Gough Nichols, Westminster, 1855 (Box 12)
    Instructs Nichols to print the accompanying letter, now missing.
  - Morgan, Charles B.
    - 5 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Old Jewry, London, 1856 Jan 5-1861 Sep 26 (Box 12)
      Letters between uncle and nephew, on legal and family matters.
    - ALS to Robert Cradock Nichols, Norwich, 1856 Dec 28 (Box 12)
      Cousins arrange business meeting.
  - Morgan, John A. 5 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1855 Oct 11-1858 Feb 20 (Box 12)
    Friendly letters between nephew and uncle.
  - Morgan, Mary (Nichols), b. 1784. 3 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Highbury, 1826 May 24 (Box 12)
    Family correspondence.
  - N., R. B. 2 ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], [n.p.], 1808 Dec 13 (Box 12)
    About mutual friends.
  - Nares, Edward, 1762-1841. ALS to Nichols & Co., Biddenden, 1814 May 22 (Box 12)
  - Nepean, Margaret (Skinner), Lady. ALS to John Nichols, Manor House, Leders, 1814 Jan 22 (Box 12)
    Concerns her estate and its history.
  - Neunberg, C. ALS to [Nichols & Co.], Stamford Barn, 1814 Apr 14 (Box 12)
    On the shipment of an order of books.
  - Newling, J. ALS to Nichols & Co., Lichfield, 1819 Aug 17 (Box 12)
    Wants to purchase the manuscript of Pegge's Collection of Lancashire Pedigrees.
  - Nichols, Anne Susannah, b. 1788. 4 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1825 Dec-1826 Dec 30 (Box 12)
    From his sister about friends, fish, and their father.
  - Nichols, Eliza (Baker), 1784-1846. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [1823] Oct 9 (Box 12)
    A personal note to her husband ("We are all as well as we can be in your absence.") written on a proof sheet from the Gentleman's Magazine, which he marked and returned with a two page reply from Glastonbury, "this decayed old town."
  - Nichols, Isabella, b. 1785
    - 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Nov 24, Dec 15 (Box 13)
      On the death of Joseph Cradock and family business.
    - 3 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Dec 12-16 (Box 13)
      Personal letters to her brother about friends, relatives, and visits.
    - ALS (draft) to John Gough Nichols, [Highbury], 1826 Sep (Box 13)
      Family news.
  - Nichols, John 1745-1826
    - ALS (draft) to William Baker, [n.p.], [1810?] Nov 5 (Box 13)
      On antiquarian and publishing matters.
    - ALS to Edmund Henry Barker, [n.p.], 1826 Jul 14 (Box 13)
    - 3 letters (copies) to Joseph Cradock, [n.p.], 1825 Jan 8-1826 Feb 14 (Box 13)
      Personal letters between old, close friends including birthday congratulations and dinner invitations.
    - 58 ALS to John Herrick, Leicester, [1791?] Mar 18-1800 Dec 17 (Box 13)
      Long correspondence about the churches, ruins, manors and citizens of Leicestershire. This material was included in Nichols's The History and Antiquities of Leicester, v. 3.
    - ALS and letter (copy) to Sir Richard Colt Hoare, [n.p.], 1819 Mar 8, 1820 Dec 14 (Box 13)
      Thanks him for his preface.
    - AL to William Hutchinson, [n.p.], 1813 Nov 29 (Box 13)
    - 15 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Jan 1-Oct 18 (Box 13)
      To his son concerning family problems and business instructions.
    - 7 ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1825 Oct 18-1826 Oct 29 (Box 13)
      To his grandson about his health and family concerns.
    - ALS to Sir Richard Phillips, [n.p.], 1811 May 3 (Box 13)
    - Letter (draft, 3d person) to William Pickering, Parliament St., 1825 Jul 17 (Box 13)
      Reveals the true author of manuscript which Pickering had just purchased.
    - ALS to Thomas Raffles, [n.p.], 1823 Jul 3 (Box 13)
    - Letter (draft) to John Roby, [n.p.], 1821 Nov 23 (Box 13)
    - AL to W. Thomson, [n.p.], 1826 Nov 13 (Box 14)
      Concerns antiquarian pursuits.
    - ALS to Dawson Turner, [n.p.], 1826 (Box 13)
    - ALS to Edmund Turnor, [n.p.], 1826 Jul 28 (Box 13)
      On the publication of some of Turnor's work in the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - ALS to Henry Woodthorpe, [n.p.], 1823 Sep 19 (Box 13)
      Asks Woodthorpe for advice concerning his Progresses of King James.
    - ALS (draft) to an unnamed recipient, Hertford Place, 1825 Oct 9 (Box 13)
      On his family.
  - Nichols, John Bowyer, 1779-1863
    - ALS to John Yonge Akerman, [n.p.], 1835 Jul 24 (Box 13)
      Sends proof and asks for its speedy return "as there is not a moment to lose in getting it printed."
    - Letter (copy) to Robert Balmanno, [n.p.], 1829 Sep (Box 13)
      Accepts invitation to "be present at the Anniversari of the ancient Temple at the citie of Noviomagus."
    - ALS to Edmund Henry Barker, Parliament St., 1827 Nov 13 (Box 13)
      About the cost of advertising space in the Gentleman's Magazine.